Samuel Crowell

<u>Samuel.a.Crowell@Vanderbilt.edu</u> <u>In https://www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-crowell</u>

Qualifications Summary

Ph.D. candidate with 5+ years of research experience utilizing machine learning and regression analysis of large data sets to drive decision making. I'm looking for a fast-paced environment where I can learn and grow my career, ideally using quantitative methods to understand and solve complex problems.

Experience

Bleecker Street Research

New York City, NY

Research Intern

5/2023 - 8/2023

- Utilized firm and industry level data to research opportunities for short biased investments.
- Uncovered anomalies in a firm's revenue reporting using Machine Learning and Regression Analysis.
- Modeled the revenue of a leading crypto exchange using high frequency transactions data.
- Gained familiarity analyzing Forms 10-k, 10-q, and other SEC public filings.

Westwood Holdings Group

Dallas, TX

Intern

6/2017 - 7/2017

- Assisted in account compliance verification by identifying clients' stated investment objectives and confirming that their portfolios matched those goals.
- Gained experience documenting client interactions with the firm's CRM platform.

Vanderbilt University

Nashville, TN

Teaching Assistant

8/2020 - Present

- Lead lectures, mentored students, and hosted weekly office hours for undergraduate level courses as a teaching assistant.
- Taught Intro Macroeconomics and the Economics of Money and Banking as full lecturer.
- Recognized in Spring 2023 when with the Rending Fels Award for Best Teaching Assistant.

Research Assistant

5/2021 - Present

- Assisted Peter L. Rousseau in the research, data analysis, and writing of multiple finance and economic history projects.
- Used machine learning and regression analysis to identify patterns in M&A activity in early 1900's industrial firms.

Education

Vanderbilt University

Nashville, TN

PhD. in Economics, 3.8 GPA

expected 5/2024

Vanderbilt University

Nashville, TN

Masters in Economics, 3.8 GPA

5/2021

Rhodes College

Memphis, TN

B.A. Economics and B.S. Mathematics, 3.9 GPA

5/2019

Selected Research

- "Import Competition and Local Liquidity: Transmission of the China Shock"
- "Q Theory of Mergers: Evidence from Early Merger Waves" with Peter L. Rousseau, PhD. and Lily Gaeto Trotter, PhD.
- "The Local Effect of Bank Concentration and Integration on Economic Growth"

Skills

Skills: Data cleaning, analysis, and machine learning in Excel, Python, and Stata. Routinely work with large datasets. Recognition: Rending Fells Award Best Graduate Teaching Assistant (2023); Tobin Project Participant (2022); Vanderbilt Graduate Tuition Award (2019-2024); Phi Beta Kappa (2019)

Volunteering: Graduate mentor, Vanderbilt Undergraduate Research Journal; Council of Economic Graduate Students (2022)